A Guide to the Papers of Booton Herndon, 1970-1988
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Booton Herndon, 1970-1988
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9859-b
This collection contains ca. 2,000 items (9 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These additional papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Booton Herndon, Charlottesville, Virginia, on June 24, 1994.
Scope and Content Information
This collection of material pertaining to the researching, writing and publication of Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks by Booton Herndon (1915 -1995), consists of ca. 2,000 items (9 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear shelf feet), ca. 1970-1988, and undated. The papers include typed manuscripts; a copy of the published book; drafts; revisions; contracts; correspondence; photographs; interviews; tear sheets; outlines; chronologies of the lives of Pickford and Fairbanks; sources and notes; material pertaining to publicity, sales, and promotion; cassette recordings; newsclippings and printed material; and a record of expenses.
The correspondence about the book and its subjects is with Herndon's agent, Sterling Lord, his publisher, Eric Swenson of W.W. Norton, the relatives and friends of Pickford and Fairbanks, including Douglas Fairbanks, Jr. and Matty Kemp, and people interested in the book, including correspondence with Ted Galvin about Douglas Fairbanks film out-takes.
The folder on interviews and short biographies contains information on the following: Johnny Mack Brown, Allan Dwan, Arthur Edeson, Lucky Humberstone, Chuck Lewis, Anita Loos, Frances Marion, Buddy Mason, Hal Mohr, Bull Montana, Mickey Neilan, Paul O'Brien, Buddy Rogers, Bobby Rose, Larry Tailer, Charles Rosher, Blanche Sweet, and Bob Thomas.
Contents List
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks (Box 1)
  First Outlines & Notes
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1976 & n.d. (Box 1)
  Outline, Chronology & List of Films
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  Chronology of the Making of the Book
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks n.d., TMs (C) (Box 1)
  First Attempt (Rejected) with autograph corrections
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks n.d., AMs & TMs; 4 folders (Box 1)
  Chapter 1-3, Rough Draft, Second Version
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1973-1975, AMs & TMs; 2 folders (Box 1)
  Rough Draft, Rejects & Early Chapters
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks n.d., AMs & TMs; 4 folders (Box 2)
  With corrections
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks n.d., AMs & TMs; 4 folders (Box 2)
  Chapter 1, Janis Party, Biograph Years, and Chapter 2 re Mary
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1975 ?, TMs (EC); 97 pages (Box 3)
  Eric Swenson's Edited Copy with autograph corrections
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks n.d., TMs; 162 pages (Box 3)
  Chapters 1-4
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1977, TMs (EC); 104 pages (Box 3)
  With autograph changes by Ms. Griggs, and Booton Herndon's reactions in red
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1977 May-Jun, TMs; 4 folders (Box 3)
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1977 May-Jun, TMs (EC); 4 folders (Box 4)
- Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1977, TMs; 3 folders (Box 4)
  Setting Copy
- Contracts 1972-1977 (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., and related material ca. 1972-1978, n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Matty Kemp, Mary Pickford Company 1973-1977 (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Sterling Lord 1970-1977 (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Eric Swenson W.W. Norton & Company 1972-1981, n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
- Correspondence & Notes re Douglas Fairbanks' Film Out-takes 1973-1978, n.d. (Box 5)
- Correspondence & Notes re Photographs of Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1973-1977, n.d. (Box 5)
- Correspondence & Notes re the Santa Fe and Union Pacific Railroads 1975-1976 (Box 5)
- Correspondence & Notes re Sources for Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1972-1977, 2 folders (Box 6)
- Correspondence re Material used in Chapter 1 of Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks 1973-1975 (Box 6)
- Correspondence re Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks After Publication 1977-1988, n.d., 2 folders (Box 6)
- Expenses ca. 1972-1976 (Box 6)
- Interviews and Short Biographies 1975-1976, n.d., 2 folders (Box 6)
- Notes re Douglas Fairbanks 1973-1976 (Box 6)
- Notes and Other Material re Douglas Fairbanks' Films 1973-1975, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Notes re Douglas Fairbanks, his Divorce, and Death n.d. (Box 7)
- Notes re General Material 1971-1977, n.d. (Box 7)
- Notes re Pickfair, Beverly Hills n.d. (Box 7)
- Notes re Mary Pickford's Early Days in Pictures n.d., 2 folders (Box 7)
- Notes re Mary Pickford n.d. (Box 7)
- Notes re Mary Pickford after his divorce from Douglas Fairbanks 1976, n.d. (Box 7)
- Notes re Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks as "King & Queen" n.d. (Box 7)
- Notes re Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks taken from Books about Hollywood and Films n.d., 2 folders (Box 8)
- Notes re the Pickford Family n.d. (Box 8)
- Notes re United Artists 1976 & n.d. (Box 8)
- Photographs used in Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks1977 (Box 8)
- Photographs rejected from use in Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks1977, 2 folders (Box 8)
- Printed Material 1970-1977, n.d. (Box 8)
- Promotion and Publicity 1977 (Box 9)
- Psychoanalysis of Douglas Fairbanks and Mary Pickford 1975-1977, n.d. (Box 9)
- Sales through Classic Film Collector 1977-1978 (Box 9)
- Tear Sheets on Douglas Fairbanks ca. 1973-1974, n.d. (Box 9)
- Tear Sheets on Mary Pickford 1971, n.d., 2 folders (Box 9)
- Printed Copy of Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks by Booton Herndon 1977 (Box 9)
- Copies of Newspaper Articles re Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks; and Four Photographs n.d. (Oversize P-17)
  Photographs of Douglas Fairbanks, Fairbanks golfing, Fairbanks posed in front of a huge map of the world, and on the set of Robinson Crusoe
- Ted Galvin, Jr., Medina, Ohio ca. 1977, Cassette Tape
  Re film out-takes from The Black Pirate starring Douglas Fairbanks, including a frame by frame description and the famous sail sequence
- Psychoanalysis of Mary Pickford and Douglas Fairbanks by Dr. Seymour Rabinowitz n.d., Cassette Tape
- Continuation of Dr. Seymour Rabinowitz's Analysis of Douglas Fairbanks n.d., Cassette Tape
  With brief notes on Charlie Rosher
- Interview re the making of the film Birth of a Nation and the beginning of the Analysis of Douglas Fairbanks by Dr. Seymour Rabinowitz n.d., Cassette Tape